梦是来自内心深处的信息
汉化：@大月半子（PPm）
https://weibo.com/baba
调轴&修正：@QianyuLi
https://subhd.tv/u/QianyuLi
我的星球 阿拉基斯 太阳落山时是如此美丽
My planet, Arrakis, is so beautiful when the sun is low.
在沙滩上翻滚……
Rolling over the sands…
你可以在空气中看到香料
You can see spice in the air.
傍晚时分 香料收割者们着陆了
At nightfall, the spice harvesters land.
外面的人争分夺秒地躲避白天的炎热
The outsiders race against time to avoid the heat of the day.
他们当着我们的面蹂躏我们的土地
They ravage our lands in front of our eyes.
我只知道他们虐待我的人民
Their cruelty to my people is all I've known.
这些外来者 哈科宁家族 早在我出生之前就来了
These outsiders, The Harkonnens, came long before I was born.
通过控制香料生产 他们变得非常富有
By controlling the spice production they became obscenely rich.
比皇帝本人还富有
Richer than the Emperor himself.
我们的战士没能从哈科宁手中救出阿拉基斯
Our warriors couldn't free Arrakis from the Harkonnens,
但是有一天 根据皇帝的命令 他们消失了
but one day, by imperial decree, they were gone.
为什么皇帝选择了这条路?下一个压迫者是谁?
Why did the Emperor choose this path? And who our next oppressors be?
10191年
YEAR 10191
厄崔迪家族的卡拉丹家园
CALADAN HOMEWORLD OF HOUSE ATREIDES
还好你早起
It's good you're up early.
父亲要你在皇帝的传令官到来之前穿上礼服
Father wants you in full dress before the Emperor's herald arrives.
礼服？军队？
Full dress? Military?
仪式
Ceremonial.
既然已经决定了 我们为什么还要经历这一切?
Why do we have to go through all of this when it's already been decided?
仪式
Ceremony.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你想要 让我给你
If you want it make me give it to you.
-用语音 -妈 我刚醒
-Use the Voice. -Mom, I just woke up.
-给我水 -杯子听不到你 给我下指令
-Give me the water. -The glass can't hear you. Command me.
把水给我
Give me the water.
-几乎 -几乎?
-Almost. -Almost?
贝尼·盖瑟瑞特的技能需要多年才能学会 保罗
Bene Gesserit skills take years to learn, Paul.
你看起来很累 做了很多梦？
You look tired. More dreams?
没有
No.
极端的温度和危险的天气事件
Extreme temperatures and treacherous weather events
使阿拉基斯城外的生活变得十分艰难
make life outside the cities of Arrakis truly hostile.
强大到足以穿透金属的沙暴
With sandstorms powerful enough to cut through the metal.
只有被称为弗里曼人的土著部落能够很好地适应并生存下来
Only the native tribes known as the Fremen have adapted well enough to survive.
弗里曼人更喜欢居住在阿拉基斯最偏远的地区
Preferring to inhabit the remotest regions of Arrakis
与被弗里曼人称为谢胡鲁德的巨型沙虫
the Fremen share the deep desert with the giant sandworms
共享深邃的沙漠
known to the Fremen as Shai-Hulud.
长期接触香料赋予了这个部落特有的蓝眼睛
Long exposure to spice has given the tribe their characteristic blue eyes,
伊巴德的眼睛
the eyes of Ibad.
关于弗里曼人的其他信息很少
Little else is known of the Fremen,
除了他们是危险和不可靠的
except that they are dangerous and unreliable.
弗莱明的攻击使香料收获变得极其危险
Fremen attacks make spice harvesting extremely hazardous.
对弗里曼人来说 香料就是神圣的迷幻剂
For the Fremen, spice is the sacred hallucinogen
它能保护生命 带来巨大的健康益处
which preserves life and brings enormous health benefits.
对于帝国来说 这种香料是由间隔行会的航海家使用的
For the Imperium, the spice is used by the navigators of the Spacing Guild
在星际间寻找安全的路径
to find safe paths between the stars.
没有香料 星际旅行是不可能的
Without spice interstellar travel is impossible,
使之成为宇宙中最有价值的物质
making it by far the most valuable substance in the universe.
微笑 格尼
Smile, Gurney.
我在微笑
I am smiling.
他们大老远过来办理这个手续要花多少钱?
How much will it cost them traveling all this way for this formality?
三个公会导航员和总计146万零62个日光用于往返
Three Guild navigators and a total of 1,460,062 solaris for the round trip.
感谢科里诺家族的沙达姆四世
By the grace of Shaddam IV of the House Corrino,
上升到已知宇宙的帕迪沙皇帝的金狮宝座
Ascendant to the Golden Lion Throne of Padishah Emperor of the Known Universe,
我站在你们面前 作为变革的先驱
I stand before you as Herald of the Change.
我们有皇室成员的见证
We are witnessed by members of the Imperial Court,
间隔公会的代表 贝尼·格塞里特的妹妹
representatives of the Spacing Guild, and a sister of the Bene Gesserit.
皇帝已经说过了:
The Emperor has spoken:
厄崔迪家族将立即接管阿拉基斯
"House Atreides shall immediately take control of Arrakis
做它的管家 ”
and serve as its steward."
你接受吗?
Do you accept?
我们是厄崔迪家族
We are the House Atreides.
没有我们不响应的召唤 我们没有背叛任何信仰
There is no call we do not answer. There is no faith that we betray.
皇帝要我们给阿拉基斯带来和平
The Emperor asks us to bring peace to Arrakis.
厄崔迪家族接受
House Atreides accepts.
厄崔迪人!
Atreides!
你的印章
Your seal.
那么 就这样了？
So, it's done?
完成了
It's done.
-是吗? -稳定器太松了
-How was it? -The stabilizers are too loose.
我会处理 -谢谢你 我的朋友
-I'll handle that. -Thank you, my friend.
邓肯 -我的孩子!
-Duncan. -My boy!
保罗,我的孩子
Paul, my boy.
那么 你明天要和先遣队去阿拉基斯吗?
So, you're going to Arrakis tomorrow with the advance team?
是的 我明天要和先遣队去阿拉基斯
Yes, I'm going to Arrakis tomorrow with the advance team.
-我想让你带我一起去 -你会吗?
-I'd like you to take me with you. -You would?
那太糟糕了 因为不
That's too bad, cause no.
邓肯……
Duncan…
你是想把我送上军事法庭吗？怎么回事？
Are you trying to give me court-martial? What's going on?
-我能相信你吗？-当然 你知道的
-Can I trust you with something? -Always. You know that.
我一直在做梦
I've been having dreams.
关于阿拉基斯和弗里曼
About Arrakis and the Fremen.
好的,那么?
Okay, so?
我看到你了
I saw you.
和弗里曼人
With the Fremen.
所以我找到他们了？那就这样吧 这是个好兆头 对吧?
So I do find them? There you go. That's a good omen right there, right?
兰维尔！
Lanville!
我看见你躺着死了 在战斗中倒下
I saw you lying dead. Fallen in battle.
我觉得如果我在那里 你就不会死
I felt like if I had been there you'd be alive.
首先 我不会死
First of, I'm not gonna die.
-你没把我当回事 -这就是你想跟我一起来的原因?
-You're not taking me seriously. -That's why you wanna come with me?
听着 梦是好的故事
Listen, dreams make good stories,
但重要的事情都是在我们醒着的时候发生的
but everything important happens when we're awake,
因为那是我们创造奇迹的地方
because that's where we make things happen.
-看看你 长点肌肉？-是吗？
-Look at you, put up some muscle? -I did?
不
No.
阿拉基斯见 我的孩子
See you in Arrakis, my boy.
父亲 我想加入邓肯·爱达荷
Father, I'd like to ask to join Duncan Idaho
明天去阿拉基斯的侦察任务
on a scout mission to Arrakis tomorrow.
我学过弗里曼语言 我会成为一个有用的人
I've studied the Fremen language. I'd be an asset.
不可能
Out of the question.
几周后你会像我们一样去阿拉基斯
You'll travel in a few weeks to Arrakis like the rest of us.
我这辈子都在训练 如果我不能……
I've been training my whole life… What is the point if I'm not allowed--
你知道为什么 保罗 你是厄崔迪家族的未来
You know why, Paul. You're the future of the House Atreides.
祖父为了运动和公牛搏斗
And grandfather fought bulls for sport.
是的 看看他的下场
Yes, look where that got him.
我需要你在我身边 当我们到达阿拉基斯时 我们将面临巨大的危险
I need you by my side. When we get to Arrakis we'll face enormous danger.
什么危险？弗里曼人？沙漠？
What danger? The Fremen? The desert?
政治风险
Political danger.
王室指望我们来领导这威胁到了皇帝
The great houses look to us for leadership and this threatens the Emperor.
把阿拉基斯从哈康人手中夺走 归我们所有
By taking Arrakis from the Harkonnens and making it ours
他为一场削弱两院的战争做了铺垫
he sets the stage for a war which would weaken both houses.
但如果我们坚定立场 利用阿拉基斯真正的力量
But if we hold firm and tap the true power of Arrakis
我们可以变得更强大
we could be stronger than ever.
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
采矿香料 让弗雷曼家族安分守舍?
Mining spice, keeping the Fremen in their place?
我们不会比哈科宁强多少
We'd be no better than Harkonnens.
不 通过与弗里曼人结盟
No. By making an alliance with the Fremen.
这就是我让邓肯·爱达荷去安排的
That's what I've sent Duncan Idaho to arrange.
这里 在卡拉丹 我们依靠空中和海上力量统治
Here, on Caladan, we've ruled by air power and sea power.
在阿拉基斯 我们需要培育沙漠力量
On Arrakis, we need to cultivate desert power.
我想让你参加我的长老会 了解我的工作
I want you sitting in on my council, learn what I do.
如果我不是呢 爸爸?
What if I'm not, dad?
不是什么?
Not what?
厄崔迪家族的未来
The future of the House Atreides.
我告诉我父亲我也不想这样
I told my father I didn't want this either.
-我想当飞行员 -你从没跟我说过
-I wanted to be a pilot. -You never told me that.
你祖父说过 “伟大的人不寻求领导
Your grandfather said, "A great man doesn't seek to lead.
他是被召唤来的 他的回答 ”
He's called to it. And he answers."
如果你的回答是“不”
And if your answer is "no"
你仍然是我唯一需要你成为的人
you'll still be the only thing I ever needed you to be,
我的孩子
my son.
我找到了自己的方法 也许你会找到你的
I found my own way to it. Maybe you'll find yours.
在他们的记忆里……
In their memory…
试试看
give it a try.
别背对着门站着
Don't stand with your back to the door.
我们要跟你说多少次?
How many times do we have to tell you?
我看你的脚步声就知道是你 格尼·哈勒克
I could tell it was you by your footsteps, Gurney Halleck.
有人可能会模仿我的步幅
Someone might imitate my stride.
我知道其中的区别 你是新的武器大师吗?
I know the difference. Are you the new weapons master?
邓肯·爱达荷走了 我必须尽我所能
With Duncan Idaho gone, I must make do as best as I can.
选择你的刀
Choose your blade.
我今天过得很不顺 格尼 给我们唱首歌吧
I've had quite a day, Gurney. Give us a song instead.
这不礼貌
That's rude.
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
老家伙
Old man.
缓慢的刀刃穿透防护罩
The slow blade penetrates the shield.
我想我今天没心情 -心情？这跟心情有什么关系?
-I'm guessing I'm not in the mood today. -Mood? What's mood got to do with it?
必要的时候就战斗 不管心情如何 现在 战斗！
You fight when the necessity arises, no matter the mood. Now, fight!
来吧!
Come on!
-我打败你了 -啊
-I have you. -Aye.
但请往下看 大人 你会和我一起死的
But look down, my lord. You'd have joined me in death.
看来你找到心情了
I see you found the mood.
-会有那么糟吗? -你不明白 是吗?
-Will it be that bad? -You don't get it, do you?
你根本不明白我们身上发生的事有多严重
You don't really understand the grave nature of what's happening to us.
80年来 阿拉基斯一直属于哈科宁家族
For 80 years Arrakis belonged to House Harkonnen.
拥有香料田80年了 你能想象有多富有吗?
Eighty years of owning the spice fields. Can you imagine the wealth?
从你的眼睛里 我要从你的眼睛里看到
In your eyes, I need to see it in your eyes.
你以前从没见过哈科宁人 我见过
You never met Harkonners before. I have.
他们不是人类 他们太残忍了！
They are not human. They're brutal!
你必须做好准备
You have to be ready.
吉迪 哈肯恩家族的主要家园
GIEDI PRIME HOMEWORLD OF HOUSE HARKONNEN
主男爵
Lord Baron.
拉班
Rabban.
我们最后一艘船已经离开阿拉基斯了 完成了
The last of our ships have left Arrakis. It's done.
很好
Very good.
叔叔 我们怎么能让这种事发生?
Uncle, how did we let this happen?
皇帝怎么能把我们建造的一切
How can the Emperor take everything we've built
都交给公爵呢？怎么能？
and give it to that Duke? How?
别太肯定 这是爱的表现
Don't be too sure, it's an act of love.
他是什么意思?
What does he mean?
什么时候礼物不是礼物?
When is a gift not a gift?
厄崔迪人的声音在上升
The Atreides Voice is rising
皇帝是个嫉妒心很强的人
and the Emperor is a jealous man.
一个危险、嫉妒的人
A dangerous, jealous man.
保罗……
Paul…
保罗 醒醒
Paul, wake up.
怎么了？-穿好衣服跟我来
-What's wrong? -Get dressed and come with me.
这是什么?
What is this?
盖乌斯·海伦·莫希姆嬷嬷来了
The Reverend Mother Gaius Helen Mohiam is here.
她是我在边·积利利学校的老师
She was my teacher at the Bene Gesserit school.
她现在是皇帝的真言者
She's now Truthsayer to the Emperor himself.
她想见见你
She would like to meet you.
为什么?
Why?
她想知道你的梦想
She wants to know about your dreams.
她怎么知道我的梦的?
How does she know about my dreams?
-岳医生为什么在这里？-他只需要一会儿
-And why is Dr. Yueh here? -He only needs a moment.
你好 少爷
Hello, young master.
你妈妈让我检查你的生命体征
Your mother asked me to check your vitals.
发生什么事情了?
What's happening?
贝尼·格塞里特声称要为更大的利益服务
Bene Gesserit claims to serve the greater good.
但恕我直言 对你的母亲
But with all due respect to your mother,
他们也为自己的议程服务
they also serve their own agenda.
你在说什么?
What are you saying?
小心点
Be careful.
他的心一如既往地坚强 夫人
His heart is strong as ever, my lady.
别把这事告诉任何人
Not a word of this to anyone.
保罗……
Paul…
记住你的训练
Remember your training.
你是谁?
Who are you?
眼里充满了反抗 就像他父亲一样
Defiance in the eyes, like his father.
离开我们
Leave us.
你必须照海伦·莫海姆嬷嬷说的做
You must do everything the Mother Helen Mohiam tells you.
你把我母亲打发到她自己家里去
You dismiss my mother in her own house.
过来 跪下
Come here. Kneel.
你怎么敢对我用语音？
How dare you use the Voice on me?
把你的右手放在盒子里
Put your right hand in the box.
你母亲叫你听我的话
Your mother bade you obey me.
我掐着你脖子上的戈姆·贾巴尔 一根毒针 立刻毙命
I hold at your neck the Gom Jabbar, a poison needle, instant death.
测试很简单
The test is simple.
把手从盒子上拿开 你就死定了
Remove your hand from the box, and you die.
盒子里有什么?
What's in the box?
疼痛
Pain.
没必要叫警卫
No need to call the guards.
你妈妈站在门后 没人能越过她
Your mother stands behind that door. No one will get past her.
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
被夹子夹住的动物会咬断自己的腿逃跑
An animal caught in a trap will gnaw off its own leg to escape.
你要做什么?
What will you do?
安静
Silence.
我不能害怕
I must not fear.
恐惧是心灵杀手
Fear is the mind-killer.
恐惧是带来毁灭的小小的死亡
Fear is the little death that brings obliteration.
我要直面我的恐惧 让它从我身上穿过去
I will face my fear and I will permit it to pass over me and through me.
当一切都过去了……
And when it has gone past…
我要用内在之眼来看清它的路径
I will turn the inner eye to see its path.
恐惧所剩无几
Where the fear has gone there will be nothing.
只有我将留下来
Only I will remain.
够了
Enough.
我们筛选人 就像用筛子筛沙
Like sifting sand through a screen, we sift people.
如果你不能像动物一样控制自己的冲动
If you had been unable to control your impulses like an animal,
我们不能让你活着
we could not have let you live.
你继承了太多权力
You inherit too much power.
-因为我是公爵的儿子吗? -因为你是杰西卡的儿子
-What, because I'm a Duke's son? -Because you are Jessica's son.
你有不止一项与生俱来的权利 孩子
You have more than one birthright, boy.
杰西卡
Jessica.
你在某种程度上训练了他
You've been training him in a Way.
-跟我说说这些梦 -我今晚喝了一杯
-Tell me about these dreams. -I had one tonight.
你看到了什么?
What did you see?
-阿拉基斯上的一个女孩 -你以前梦到过她吗?
-A girl on Arrakis. -Have you dreamt of her before?
很多次了
Many times.
你是否经常梦见事情就像你梦见的那样发生?
Do you often dream things that happen just as you dreamt them?
不完全是
Not exactly.
再见,年轻的人类 我希望你能活下去
Goodbye, young human. I hope you'll live.
你非得走那么远吗?
Did you have to go that far?
你选择用这种方式训练他 无视规则
You chose to train him in the Way in defiance of the rule.
他利用我们的力量 他必须接受极限测试
He wields our power. He had to be tested to the limits.
在男性身上浪费了这么多的潜力
So much potential wasted in the male.
你被告知只生女儿
You were told to bear only daughters,
但你和你的骄傲以为你能制造出奎维兹·哈达拉赫
but you and your pride thought you could produce the Kwisatz Haderach.
是我错了吗?
Was I wrong?
他没死在那间屋子里算你走运
You're lucky he didn't die in that room.
如果他是那个人 他还有很长的路要走
If he is The One he has a long way to go.
他的视力刚刚苏醒 现在他被扔进了火里
His sight is barely awakened and now he goes into the fire.
但我们的计划是以世纪为单位的
But our plans are measured in centuries.
我们还有其他的前景
We have other prospects
如果他没有信守诺言
if he fails his promise.
你看到的希望如此渺茫吗?
Do you see so little hope?
在阿拉基斯 我们已经尽力了
On Arrakis, we have done all we can for you.
道路已经铺设好了 希望他不会把钱挥霍掉
The path has been laid. Let's hope he doesn't squander it.
保罗……
Paul…
这是什么意思?
What does it mean?
-我能成为那个人吗？-你听到了？
-That I can be The One? -You heard?
贝尼·格塞特家族是大家族的有力合作伙伴
The Bene Gesserit serve as powerful partners to the great houses,
但还有更多的原因
but there's more to it.
你从暗处搅乱了帝国的政治
You stir the politics on the Imperium from the shadows.
-我知道 -你又不是什么都知道
-I know. -You don't know everything.
几千年来
For thousands of years,
我们一直在小心翼翼地杂交血统以产生……
we've been carefully crossing bloodlines to bring forth--
救世主？
The One?
一个……
A mind…
足够强大的头脑 能够突破时空、过去和未来……
powerful enough to breach space and time, past and future…
帮助我们走向更美好的未来的人
who can help us into a better future.
我们认为他已经很接近了
We think he's very close now.
有人相信他就在这里
Some believe he is here.
这都是计划的一部分
All part of the plan.
盾牌
Shields.
“我的肺品味着时光的气息 吹过流沙 ”
"My lungs taste the air of Time, Blown past falling sands."
苏菲尔·哈瓦特
Thufir Hawat.
少爷 行走在新世界的感觉如何?
Young master, how does it feel to walk on the new world?
至少可以说 这是令人兴奋的
Exciting, to say the least.
-大人 -你好吗 老朋友?
-My Lord. -How are you, old friend?
我的先遣队已经把守了这座城市
My advance team has secured the city.
我们还在解决一些棘手的问题
We're still smoothing out a few rough spots.
我的夫人
My Lady.
利桑·盖布！
Lisan al-Gaib!
别被这种欢迎所愚弄
Don't be fooled by the welcome.
他们遵循老主人的规矩 强制出勤
They follow their old master's rules, mandatory attendancy.
这就是哈科宁的爱
That's Harkonnen love out there.
厄崔迪人!
Atreides!
让我们让你们远离太阳
Let's get you out of the sun.
这个地方热得要命
The heat can kill in this place.
他们在指着我们
They were pointing at us.
他们在喊什么?
What were they shouting?
利桑·盖布 “来自外部世界的声音”
Lisan al-Gaib. "The Voice from the Outer World."
这是他们对"弥赛亚"的称呼
It's their name for "messiah."
这意味着贝尼·格塞里特在这里做了一些工作
That means that Bene Gesserit have done a work here.
种植迷信？
Planting superstitions?
准备上路 保罗
Preparing the way, Paul.
这些人等利桑·盖布已经等了几个世纪了
These people have waited for centuries for the Lisan al-Gaib.
他们看到了你 看到了征兆
They see you, they see the signs.
他们看到的是他们被告知要看到的
They see what they've been told to see.
我们可以出发了
We're good to go.
盾墙 保护城市不受天气和蠕虫的侵袭
Shield wall, protects the city from the weather and the worms.
当地人称这个大的为“上帝之手”
The locals call the big one the "Hand of God."
嗯 上帝之手正在破坏我们的通讯系统
Well, the Hand of God is wreaking havoc on our com system.
太安静了
It's so quiet.
是的 这也是我担心的
Yeah. That's what worries me too.
有一个太空港
There's a space port,
在那堆尘土里有个香料精炼厂
and in that plump of dust there's a spice refinery.
我们最薄弱的两个环节 我要你看守他们
Our two most vulnerable points. I want you guarding them.
如果我们不能提炼香料并将其运往世界各地 我们就死定了
If we can't refine spice and ship it off to the world, we're dead here.
太阳升得太高了 我们得把门锁上
The sun is getting too high. We need to seal the doors.
他们怎么说这个鬼地方来着?
What do they say about this hell hole again?
"这是阵雨 你用沙子擦屁股"
"It's a shower, you scrub your ass with sand,"
大人 他们是这么说的
My Lord, that's what they say.
他们是这么说的
That's what they say.
管家的候选人 夫人
Candidates for a house keeper, my lady.
你叫什么名字? -沙达·梅普斯 夫人
-What is your name? -Shadout Mapes, my lady.
剩下的人可以走了 谢谢
The rest of you may go. Thank you.
沙达
Shadout.
这是一个古老的查科布萨单词
It's an old chakobsa word.
“七星”
"Well dipper."
你是弗里曼人
You are Fremen.
-你知道古代语言吗? -我知道很多事情
-You know the ancient tongues? -I know many things.
我知道你的身体里藏着武器
I know that you have a weapon concealed in your bodies.
等等
Wait.
如果你想伤害我 我必须警告你不管你隐瞒了什么
If you mean to harm me, I must warn you whatever you're hiding,
这还不够
it won't be enough.
如果你真的是救世主
My weapon is meant as a gift
我的武器就是一份礼物
if you are truly The One.
你知道这个吗?
Do you know this?
这是一把水晶刀
It's a crysknife.
你知道它的意思吗?
Do you know its meaning?
做好准备
Be ready.
是个制造者
It's a maker.
一个沙漠深处的制造者
A maker of the deep desert.
当你在一个预言中生活了这么久
When you have lived with a prophecy for so long
揭露真相的时刻令人震惊
the moment of revelation is a shock.
利桑·盖布 母亲和儿子
Lisan al-Gaib. The mother and the son.
是你的
It is yours.
沙胡鲁德的牙齿
Tooth of Shai-Hulud.
你好
Hello.
你不该在这个时候出来
You shouldn't be out here at this time of the day.
他们在外面
They are out here.
弗里曼朝圣者 他们不在乎中暑
Fremen pilgrims. They don't care about heat stroke.
我不知道这里还能找到椰枣树
I didn't know date palms could even be found out here.
这些不是土著 没有我 他们无法生存
These aren't indigenous. They can't survive without me.
每天喝一份相当于五个人的量
Each one of these drinks every day the equivalent of five man.
二十棵棕榈树 一百条生命
Twenty palm trees. A hundred lives.
-我们应该去除它们？拯救水？ -不 不
-Should we remove them? Save the water? -No, no.
这些都是神圣的
These are sacred.
旧的梦想
Old dream.
阿拉基斯岛上最大、最危险的生物是沙虫
The largest and the most dangerous organism on Arrakis is the sandworm.
长度可达400米
Capable of reaching 400 meters in length.
为了避免发出有节奏的声音来吸引沙虫
To avoid making rhythmic noises which attract the sandworms,
弗里曼人用沙路穿越沙漠
the Fremen cross desert spaces using the sand walk,
一种节奏不规则的舞蹈动作
a dance-like motion with irregular rhythm
它模仿了沙漠的自然声音
which emulates the natural sounds of the desert.
阿拉基斯岛上的植物如此稀少都要感谢弗里曼人
What scant plant life exists on Arrakis is thanks to the Fremen,
他们种植了深根的地形植物
who have cultivated deep-rooted terrain plants,
比如仙人掌 矮树丛
such as saguaro, burrobush,
沙马鞭草和香丛
sand verbena and incense bush.
牧羊人树有最深厚的历史渊源
The shepherd's tree has the deepest documented roots,
延伸超过450英尺深
stretching more than 450 feet deep.
这些植物在干旱贫瘠的土地上紧紧抓住生命不放
These plants cling to life in a parched nutrient-poor landscape.
这是一个寻猎者 操作者一定在附近
It's a hunter-seeker. The operator must be nearby.
哈科宁特工六周前就被固定在那个洞里了
The Harkonnen agent was cemented into that hole six weeks ago.
让寻猎者通过墙内的水管进入
Manned the hunter-seeker through a water pipe inside the walls.
先生 我今天让你失望了 没有借口
Sir, I failed you today. There's no excuse.
我已经向你递交了辞呈
You have my resignation.
-你要剥夺我们的天赋? -先生 法官大人要求……
-You'd deprive us of your talents? -Sir, my honor demands--
他们想要我儿子的命!
They tried to take the life of my son!
我才不管什么法官大人 你要宽恕吗？去抓间谍
I don't give a damn about your honor. You want absolution? Go catch some spies.
陛下
Your Grace.
那东西必须离开
The thing must leave.
你可以毫无畏惧地说话 我们的宠物听不懂你的语言
You can speak without fear. Our pet doesn't understand your language.
滚出去!
Get out!
它理解 激活沉默
It understands. Activate silence.
皇帝的信息是什么?
What is the Emperor's message?
他会加强你的力量
He will strengthen your hand.
和他的萨尔道卡尔军队…
With his Sardaukar army…
绝不能让人知道
It must never be known.
阿拉基斯上空没有卫星 厄崔迪人会死在黑暗中
There's no satellites over Arrakis. The Atreides would die in the dark.
在那件事上
On that matter.
莱托·厄崔迪公爵对我们来说毫无意义
Duke Leto Atreides means nothing to our order.
但他的妻子在我们的保护之下 也就是她的儿子
But his wife is under our protection, and by extension, her son.
给他们放逐的尊严吧
Allow them the dignity of exile.
哈科嫩家族绝不会想要破坏你们神圣的秩序
House Harkonnen would never dream of violating the sanctity of your order.
我向你保证 我们不会伤害他们
I give you my word. We would not harm them.
-如果公爵的儿子活下来……-没有厄崔迪人会活下来
-If the Duke's son lives-- -No Atreides will live.
大人 你向女巫保证过 她看到的太多了
My Lord, you gave your word to the witch. And she sees too much.
我说过我不会伤害他们 我不会的
I said I would not harm them. And I shall not.
但阿拉基斯就是阿拉基斯
But Arrakis is Arrakis,
沙漠带走了弱者
and the desert takes the weak.
我的沙漠
My desert.
我的阿拉基斯
My Arrakis.
我的沙丘
My dune.
你的第一次战略会议
Your first strategy meeting.
保罗·阿特里德斯 他赤手空拳抓住了寻猎者就像一个英雄
Paul Atreides, who catches hunter-seekers in his bare hands like a hero of all.
-谢谢你羞辱我 老家伙 -我会盯着你的
-Thanks for the humiliation, old man. -I'll keep an eye on you.
注意!
Attention!
让我们开始吧
Let's get started.
苏菲尔 操作
Thufir, operations.
我拿到了一份哈科宁的账簿
I've secured a copy of the Harkonnen's account books.
哈科宁人每年从这里拿走100亿日光
The Harkonnens were taking 10 billion solaris out of here every year.
“他们要吸取丰富的海洋
"They shall suck at the abundance of the seas
还有藏在沙子里的宝藏 ”
and on the treasures hidden in the sand."
短期内我们不会看到这样的利润
We won't see profits like that for a while,
用他们留给我们的设备就不行
not with the equipment they left us.
情况有多糟?
How bad is it?
这些是香料筒仓
These are spice silos.
我们要把每条板条箱都装满
We are meant to fill every crate.
都是吗？
All of them?
每25个标准天
Every 25 standard days.
哈科宁的破坏行动拖了我们的后腿
Harkonnen sabotage slows us down.
但是谁来仲裁呢?
But who's meant to arbitrate?
难道就没有一个变革的法官来监督这个转变吗?
Isn't there a Judge of the Change to oversee the transition?
-皇帝任命了谁？-列特·凯恩斯博士 帝国生态学家
-Who did the Emperor appoint? -Dr. Liet Kynes, imperial ecologist.
我在这里已经20年了 跟别人告诉我的不一样
Been here 20 years. Eccentric from what I'm told.
我想亲眼看看这些收获地
I want to see these harvesting fields myself.
我不建议你这么做 大人
I wouldn't recommend it, my lord.
让这位变化的法官陪着我们
Have this Judge of the Change accompany us.
我们的会议早该举行了
Our meeting is long overdue.
我们会得到一点帝国的保护
And we'll get a bit of imperial protection.
人质？我喜欢
A hostage? I love it.
他来了 大人
He's here, my lord
照顾好他们 他们是朋友
Take care of them, they are friends.
邓肯!-我的孩子!
-Duncan! -My boy!
-我发誓你长高了 -嗯 你闻起来更臭了
-I swear you're getting taller. -Well, you smell much worse.
我和弗里曼人住了四周
For four weeks I've lived with the Fremen,
藏在沙漠里 在一个叫做西斯的社区里
hidden in the desert, in the community called the sietch.
斯蒂格 那个西斯的首领跟我来见你了 先生
Stilgar, the leader of that sietch has come with me to meet you, sir.
-这个西斯是怎么藏起来的? -是在地下
-This sietch, how was it hidden? -It's under ground.
阿拉基斯到处都是洞穴
Arrakis is filled with caverns.
那地方有多大?
How big was the place?
这里有一万人 还有几百个西斯
It's a ten thousand people, and there are hundreds of sietches.
数以百万计的弗里曼人n 你是对的
Millions of Fremen. You were right.
哈科宁估计整个星球上有五万人
The Harkonnen estimate was fifty thousand on the whole planet.
弗里曼人看着我找了好几天 我从没见过他们
The Fremen watched me search for them for days. I never saw them.
最后 他们派了一个战士来杀我
Finally, they sent a warrior out to kill me,
我必须告诉你 我从未如此接近死亡
and I have to tell you, I've never come so close to dying.
帝国里没有比他更好的战士了
There's no finer fighter in the Imperium.
-他们像恶魔一样战斗 -沙漠的力量
-They fight like demons. -Desert power.
邓肯 做得好 -谢谢您 大人
-Duncan, well done. -Thank you, my lord.
长官 他们的首领有把刀他不会投降的
Sir, their leader has a knife he won't surrender, sir.
是一把水晶刀 对他的族人来说是神圣的
It's a crysknife, it's sacred to his people.
让他过去
Let him pass.
就此止步
Stop there.
嘿!嘿!
Hey! Hey!
斯蒂尔加 欢迎
Stilgar, welcome.
先生 我尊重任何尊重我的人的人格尊严
Sir, I respect the personal dignity of any man that respects mine.
拿着
Hold.
谢谢你 斯蒂格 给了你身体水分
Thank you, Stilgar, for the gift of your body's moisture.
我们以给予它的精神接受它
We accept it in the spirit in which it was given.
我很高兴你来了
I'm glad you've come.
我相信你们的人和我的人有很多可以互相提供的东西
I believe your people and mine have much to offer one another.
你们是外地人 你们来这里是为了香料
You are outworlders, you come here for the spice,
你拿走它 不付出任何回报
You take it, giving nothing in return.
这是真的
That's true.
我知道你被哈科宁折磨过
I know you've suffered at the hands of the Harkonnen.
说出你想要的名字
Name what you want.
如果在我的权力范围内 我会给予 不求任何回报
If it's in my power to grant I'll give it and ask for nothing.
我要求的是：不要找我们的西斯 不要侵入我们的土地
I ask for this: do not seek our sietches, do not trespass in our lands.
早在你来之前 沙漠就属于我们了
The desert was ours long before you came.
所以 来挖出你的香料
So, come and dig your spice,
但当你有了它 回到盾墙的这一边
but when you have it, go back to this side of the shield wall
把沙漠留给弗里曼人
and leave the desert to the Fremen.
你要称呼公爵为“大人”或“先生”
You will address the Duke as "my lord," or "sir."
格尼 等……等一下
Gurney, just… Just a moment.
皇帝把阿拉基斯作为我的封地交给我管理和保护
The Emperor has given me Arrakis as my fief to rule and protect.
如果责任迫使我 我不能答应不去沙漠旅行
I cannot promise not to travel into the desert if duty compels me.
但你的西斯将永远属于你
But your sietches will be yours forever.
在我统治这里的时候你永远不会被追捕
and you will never be hunted while I govern here.
这很光荣
That's very honorable.
我必须走了
I must go.
这就是我要对你说的
That's all I have to say to you.
你为什么不留下来 我们将向您致敬
Why don't you stay. We would honor you.
法官要求我去别处
Honor requires that I be elsewhere.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
-我不喜欢他 -我们的计划卓有成效
-I don't like him. -Our plan bears fruit.
但这需要时间
But it will take time.
是的 这需要时间
Yes. It will take time.
给 这是给你的
Here, this is for you.
这是一个副罗盘
It's a paracompass.
这里的卫星有磁场 所以简单的罗盘指针不会指向北方
The moons here have a magnetic field, so a simple compass needle won't point north.
需要一个巧妙的发条装置来解决这个问题
Takes a clever piece of clockwork to sort it out.
这些是弗雷曼人做的吗?
Do Fremen make these?
仍然适合 压砂机 和各种巧妙的东西
And stillsuits, and sand compactors, and all kinds of ingenious things.
什么是压砂机?
What the hell is a sand compactor?
那是一个压砂机
That's a sand compactor.
天啊 你已经变成乡巴佬了
My God, man, you've gone native.
你欣赏他们
You admire them.
是的
I do.
他们凶猛但忠诚
They're fierce but loyal.
他们适应了沙漠 沙漠是他们的一部分 也是他们的一部分
They're tuned into the desert, part of it, it's part of them.
你等着瞧吧
You wait till you see it.
外面很美
It's beautiful out there.
日出警告
Sunrise warning.
温度高达140度 现在温度是90度
…The temperature up to 140 degrees. The temperature now is 90 degrees.
但十分钟后气温会上升50度
But it will rise 50 degrees in ten minutes.
最后一次警告
Last warning.
法官的变化 先生
The Judge of the Change, sir.
列特·凯恩斯博士
Dr. Liet Kynes.
大人 公爵 欢迎来到阿拉基斯
My Lord, Duke, welcome to Arrakis.
你是帝国的生态学家
You are the imperial ecologist.
谢谢你的蒸馏服
Thank you for the stillsuits.
这是弗里曼人做的 最好的
They are Fremen make, the best.
“如果您允许的话 先生 我必须检查一下完好……
With your permission, sir, I must check the integrity--
没关系
It's all right.
凯恩斯医生 我们听你的了
Dr. Kynes, we're in your hands.
蒸馏服是一种高效的过滤系统
A stillsuit is a high-efficiency filtration system.
即使是这么早
Even this early in the morning
没有这个你撑不过两小时
you wouldn't survive two hours without one of these.
它能使身体降温 并将流失的水分循环用于出汗
It cools the body and recycles the water lost to sweat.
你的身体动作提供了能量
Your bodies movements provide the power.
在面罩里面 你会发现一根管子 可以让你喝到循环水
Inside the mask you'll find a tube to allow you to drink the recycled water.
在良好的工作状态下 你的西装每天损失的水不会超过一顶针
In good-working order your suit won't lose more than a thimble full of water a day.
非常令人印象深刻
Most impressive.
让我看看你 小伙子
Let's have a look at you, lad.
-你以前穿过蒸馏服吗? -没有 这是我的第一次
-You've worn a stillsuit before? -No, this is my first time.
你的沙漠靴在脚踝处以一种滑脱的方式脱下来 谁教你这么做的?
Your desert boots off at a slip fashion at the ankles. Who taught you to do that?
这似乎是正确的方式
It seemed the right way.
“他会知道他的习惯 就像他生来就知道一样 ”
"He will know his customs as if he was born with them."
你是弗里曼人？
Are you a Fremen?
我在西斯和村里都被接纳了
I am accepted in both sietch and village.
现在
Now.
来看看你赖以为生的香料沙吧
Come and see the spice sands on which your livelihood depends.
如果你的扑翼机掉到这里 你会怎么做?
What would you do if your ornithopter went down out here?
你不会想去那里的 是蠕虫的领土
You wouldn't want to go down out there. It's worm territory.
尘云
Dust cloud.
我看到了
I see it.
那是你的一辆矿车
That's one of your harvesters.
你可以看到香料散布在表面
You can see the spice scattered over the surface.
丰富的香料床的颜色
Rich spice bed by the color.
如果你再高一点 你就能看得更清楚了
If you get a little higher you'll have a better view.
你看到这些侦察机在寻找蠕虫踪迹
You see these spotter aircraft looking for worm sign.
蠕虫踪迹？
Worm sign?
一股沙波向履带移动
A sand wave moving toward the crawler.
蠕虫在深处移动 但当它们攻击时 会更接近表面
Worms travel deep but get closer to the surface when they attack.
如果你有耐心 我们会看到的
If you are patient we should see one.
蠕虫总来？-是的 它们被有节奏的声音吸引
-Worm always comes? -Always, they're drawn by rhythmic noises.
我们为什么不直接保护那些履带车呢?
Why don't we just shield the crawlers?
在沙漠中 盾牌就是死刑
A shield is a death sentence in the desert.
它吸引蠕虫 驱使它们疯狂地杀戮
It attracts the worms and drives them into a killing frenzy.
那是虫子吗?
Is that a worm?
大的
Big one.
你的眼力真好
You have good eyes.
呼叫履带车德尔塔阿贾克斯9号 蠕虫踪迹警告 告知收悉
Calling crawler Delta Ajax 9. Worm sign warning. Acknowledge.
谁呼叫德尔塔阿贾克斯9号？完毕
Who calls Delta Ajax 9? Over.
-他们看起来很冷静 -非上市航班 帝国业务
-They seem pretty calm about it. -Unlisted flight, Imperium business.
蠕虫踪迹 在你的北面和东面 3.7公里
Worm sign, north and east of you. 3.7 kilometers.
德尔塔阿贾克斯9号 我是1号侦察机 蠕虫踪迹确认
Delta Ajax 9, this is Spotter 1, worm sighting confirmed.
等待联系修复
Standby for contact fix.
蠕虫正在拦截你的位置 五分钟后联系
Worm is on intercept course to your position. Contact in five minutes.
那么现在会发生什么呢?
So what happens now?
他们会叫搬运工来抬履带
They'll call the carryall to lift the crawler.
他们会在最后一刻收获
They'll harvest right up to the last minute.
呼叫阿尔法零号载客 准备停靠
Calling carryall Alfa Zero. Ready to docking sequence.
五分钟后联系 完毕
Contact five minutes, over.
有人看到载客了吗?
Anybody got a visual on a carryall?
在那儿
There it is.
我是阿尔法零号载客至德尔塔阿贾克斯9号
This is carryall Alfa Zero to Delta Ajax 9.
从你的东面靠近
Approaching from your east.
调整高度 准备对接和抓握
Correcting altitude and preparing docking and gripping.
收到 阿尔法零号 启动对接序列
Copy, Alpha Zero. Initiating docking sequence.
-T-5 -收到
-T-5. -Copy that.
-30秒后准备升空 -对接启动序列
-Prepare to be airborne in 30 seconds. -Docking sequence initiated.
你们要做好准备
Brace yourselves.
阿尔法零号 我们只剩一个接触点了
Alpha Zero, we are short on one point of contact.
-怎么回事? -这是一个锚 它坏了
-What is going on? -It's one of the anchors. It's dead.
该死
Shit.
载客 无法继续 没有那个锚就举不起来
Carryall, unable to proceed. Unable to lift without that anchor.
呼叫全体 呼叫全体
All call. All call.
区域内任何载客 请回答
Any carryall in the sector, please respond.
一号观察员 汇报最新情况 完毕
Spotter 1, give us an update. Over.
液压已经坏了 我们赶不上了 你们必须撤离
Hydraulics are dead. We won't make it. You have to evacuate.
-那个履带车上有多少人？-21个
-How many men on that crawler? -Crawler of 21.
-我们的每个船能载六个人 -那还差三个人
-Our ships can take six each. -That's still three short.
我们会有办法的
We'll find a way.
我是莱托·厄崔迪公爵
This is Duke Leto Atreides.
我们要下去营救德尔塔阿贾克斯9号的船员
We're coming down to extract the crew of Delta Ajax 9.
坐在左边
Sit down on the left.
防护罩发电机每台重100公斤
The shield generators weigh 100 kilos each.
是的 格尼 让我们的护卫把防护罩发电机扔了
Yes, Gurney, have our escort throw out the shield generators.
保罗 我要你在旋翼机后面 引导他们
And Paul, I want you at the back of the thopter, guide them in.
德尔塔阿贾克斯9号 给我的船各派7个人
Delta Ajax 9, put seven men each in my ships now.
两分钟后联系
Contact in two minutes.
快到了 伙计们 我们最好现在弃船
It's getting close, guys. We better abandon the ship now.
他们在哪儿?
Where are they?
长官 这是有原因的
Sir, there is protocol for a reason,
如果我们再走一步 我们就死定了
if we take one step out we're as good as dead.
再说了 我们有很多香料 我们不能就这么走了
Besides, we've got full load of spice, we can't just leave--
该死的香料!我要所有人马上离开那艘船!
Damn the spice! I want every man off that crawler now!
七个在这里 七个在那里!
Seven over here, seven over there!
快跑 快跑!
Run, run!
克维萨茨·哈德拉赫
Kwisatz Haderach.
克维萨茨·哈德拉赫醒了
Kwisatz Haderach awakes.
快点!上来!
Hurry! Get on!
它来了!
It's here!
保罗!
Paul!
我认得你的脚步声 老家伙
I recognize your footsteps, old man.
起来 我们走吧
Get up. Let's go.
你怎么了？来吧 我们走吧
What's wrong with you? Come on. Let's go.
快跑!
Run!
“祝福造物主和他的水 祝福他的来去
"Bless the Maker and His water. Bless the coming and going of Him.
愿上帝的降临净化世界 将世界留给他的子民 ”
May His passage cleanse the world. And keep the world for His people."
-嘿 你不能冒这个险 -是的,先生
-Hey, you cannot take such risks. -Yes, sir.
-你有责任 -对不起 先生 不会再发生了
-You do have responsibilities. -I'm sorry, sir. It won't happen again.
凯恩斯博士
Dr. Kynes.
你亲眼所见
You saw it with your own eyes.
这是显而易见的 他们留给我们的一切都是一团糟
It's plain to see. Everything they've left us is in shambles.
我们注定要失败
We've been set up to fail.
那个载客太旧了 沙漠对设备不友好
That carryall was just old. The desert isn't kind to equipment.
你知道如果我不让香料生产重回正轨会发生什么吗?
You know what will happen if I don't get spice production back on track?
我不是来帮你的
I'm not here to take your part.
阿拉基斯见过像你这样的人来来去去
Arrakis has seen men like you come and go.
照顾好你的家人
Take good care of your family.
沙漠对人类也不好
The desert's not kind to humans either.
香料是一种精神活性化学物质 你似乎很敏感
Spice is a psychoactive chemical. You seem to be sensitive.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
谢谢你 岳医生
Thank you, Dr. Yueh.
这不是过敏反应
It wasn't an allergic reaction.
我有一个幻觉
I had a vision.
我的眼睛睁得大大的
My eyes were wide open.
你看到了什么?
What did you see?
克维萨茨·哈德拉赫……
Kwisatz Haderach…
你可以看到
You can see.
真让人困惑 我以为我看到了自己的死亡 其实不是
It's confusing, I thought I saw my death, only it wasn't.
我知道刀很重要
I know a knife is important somehow.
有人会递给我一把刀
Someone will hand me a blade.
但我不知道是谁 何时何地
But I don't know who or when or where.
有些事情是非常清楚的 我能感觉到
Some things though are crystal clear. I can feel it.
我知道你怀孕了
I know you're pregnant.
你不可能知道
You can't know that.
我几乎不知道 而且才过了几周
I barely know that and it's only been few weeks.
萨鲁萨·塞孔杜斯帝国军队星球
SALUSA SECUNDUS IMPERIAL ARMY PLANET
男爵找我们干什么?
What does the Baron want with us?
哈科宁人比厄崔迪人多
The Harkonnen outnumber Atreides.
厄崔迪军团是帝国中最好的
Atreides legions are the finest in the Imperium.
由格尼·哈勒克和邓肯·爱达荷培训
Trained by Gurney Halleck and Duncan Idaho.
我们是萨道迦人 皇帝的精英 任何违抗我们的人都会被打倒
We are the Sardaukar, the Emperor's elite. Anyone who defies us will fall.
就这样
Just so.
按约定分为三个营
Three battalions as agreed.
如皇帝所命 一定会成功的
As the the Emperor commands. It will be done.
有些关于保罗的事你得知道
There's something you need to know about Paul.
不 我不想知道
No. I don't think I wanna know.
自从你把他带到你的嬷嬷面前
Ever since you brought him before your Reverend Mother
他已经不一样了
he hasn't been the same.
他心烦意乱
He's distracted.
杰西卡 你给我生了个儿子
Jessica, you gave me a son.
从他出生的那一刻起 我从未质疑过你
And from the moment he was born I never questioned you.
我完全信任你 即使你走在阴影里
I trusted you completely, even when you walked in shadows.
现在我只问你一件事
Now I'm asking you this one thing.
如果发生什么事你会保护我们的儿子吗?
If anything happens will you protect our son?
与我的生活
With my life.
我不是在问他妈妈 我在问贝尼·格塞特
I'm not asking his mother, I'm asking the Bene Gesserit.
你会保护保罗吗?
Will you protect Paul?
你为什么会有这些想法?
Why are you having these thoughts?
莱托 这不是你
Leto, this is not you.
我以为我们会有更多的时间
I thought we'd have more time.
-晚安 保罗大师 -晚安 岳医生
-Have a good night, Master Paul. -Good night, Dr. Yueh.
你需要睡觉
You need to sleep.
不 不是那样的
No, not like that.
我应该嫁给你的
I should have married you.
哈瓦特 保安
Hawat. Security.
保安!
Security!
先生,先生
Sir. Sir.
防护罩坏了
The shield's come down.
上帝在天堂
God in Heaven.
所有带枪的东西都离开地面！走！
Get everything with guns off the ground! Go!
和我一起！
With me!
厄崔迪人!
Atreides!
萨尔多卡！
Sardaukar!
对不起 大人
I'm sorry, my lord.
但我和男爵做了个交易
But I've made a bargain with the Baron.
-为什么? -我别无选择
-Why? -I had no choice.
哈科宁人抓走了我妻子 万娜
The Harkonners have my wife, Wanna.
他们把她像洋娃娃一样拆开
They take her apart like a doll.
我会为她赎身 而你就是代价
I will buy her freedom and you are the price.
保罗 我会尽我所能
For Paul. I will do what I can.
你会为我杀人
And you will kill a man for me.
我要给你换一颗假牙
I'm going to replace your peg tooth.
如果你用力咬 这颗牙就会碎裂
If you bite them hard, this tooth will crash.
呼出空气 你就会让空气充满毒素
Breathe out, and you will fill the air with poison.
这将是你的最后一口气
It will be your last breath.
但如果你选对时机
But if you choose your moment well
也会是男爵的
it will also be the Baron's.
保罗
Paul.
我们要把他们丢在沙漠里 让他们去吃虫子
We will drop them in the desert, and leave them to the worms.
为什么不直接割了他们的喉咙呢?
Why not just cut their throats?
他们可能会使用真言者
They might use a Truthsayer.
那我们就可以诚实地说我们没杀他们
Then we can honestly say that we didn't kill them.
有伤疤的那个是聋子
The one with the scar is deaf.
见鬼去吧 狗！
To hell, dogs!
我从来没有出身高贵的人
I've never had a high-born.
-你呢? -边·积利利不是贵族
-You? -Bene Gesserit ain't no high-born.
对我来说 她出身高贵
She is high-born enough for me.
让我们喂孩子吃虫子 然后和她好好道别
Let's feed the kid to the worms and give her a long goodbye.
你敢碰我妈妈
Don't you dare touch my mother.
别说话
Don't talk.
不 你没有准备好
No. You're not ready.
去掉她的堵嘴
Remove her gag.
闭嘴
Shut up.
找到合适的语气
Find the right tone.
我们足够远 让我们把这男孩扔下去
We're far enough. Let's throw the boy off.
去掉她的堵嘴
Remove her gag.
杀了他
Kill him.
让我们自由
Set us free.
住手 割绳子
Stop. Cut the rope.
把刀给我
Give me the knife.
你太用力了
Your pitch was too forced.
这是弗雷姆基特
It's a Fremkit.
他们把船弄坏了
They've crippled the ship.
你的厨房真棒 表弟
You have a wonderful kitchen, cousin.
这是岳医生的笔迹
This is Dr. Yueh's handwriting.
“如果有人能活着逃出阿拉金 那弗雷姆基特就有厄崔迪灯塔
"If anyone makes it out of Arrakeen alive there's an Atreides beacon in the Fremkit.
上帝保佑他们能找到你 ”
God willing they'd be able to find you."
男爵阁下 岳医生
Milord Baron, Dr. Yueh.
叛徒?
The traitor?
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我干扰了他们的通讯 降低了他们的盾牌
I jammed their comms and lowered their shields.
我给了你杜克和他的家人
I gave you Duke and his family.
这笔交易是严格履行的 我能为你做什么呢?
The bargain to the letter. And what was I to do for you?
把我妻子从痛苦中解救出来
Deliver my wife from her agony.
是的
Yes.
我说我会放了她 你可以加入她
I said I'd set her free, that you could join her.
那就加入她吧
So join her.
你认为接下来会发生什么?
What do you think is next?
这是一个巨人
It's a thumper.
没有蒸馏服
No stillsuits.
我们真正需要的东西
The one thing we actually need.
几百年来 我们一直用鲜血换鲜血
For hundreds of years we've traded blood for blood.
但仅此而已
But no more.
你儿子死了 你的情妇死了
Your son is dead. Your concubine is dead.
今晚 厄崔迪家族倒下了……
Tonight the house Atreides falls…
你的血统将永远消失
and your bloodline ends forever.
你说什么?
What did you say?
“我在这里 我还在这里！”
"Here I am, here I remain!"
-凯恩斯! -你在这里不安全
-Kynes! -It's not safe for you here.
你能告诉大地之王我们是怎么被背叛的吗?
Will you tell the Great House of the Landsraad how we were betrayed?
他们中最好的人是怎么被谋杀的?
How the best of them were murdered?
我被命令什么也不能说 什么也不能看
I am commanded to say nothing, to see nothing.
皇帝派我们来这里送死
The Emperor sent us here to die.
罐里有香料
Spice in the tank.
那就是未来 它来了
That's the future. It's coming.
圣战像一团不灭的火焰在宇宙中蔓延
The Holy war is spreading across the universe like an unquenchable fire.
保罗 你害怕了 我能看到 请告诉我 你害怕什么?
Paul, you're scared. I can see it. Tell me, please, what do you fear?
-谁来帮帮我 -保罗……
-Somebody help me, please. -Paul…
它来了
It's coming.
圣战像一团不灭的火焰在宇宙中蔓延
The Holy war is spreading across the universe like an unquenchable fire.
一个以我父亲之名挥舞着厄崔迪旗帜的战士宗教
A warrior religion that waves the Atreides banner in my father's name.
狂热的军团崇拜我父亲的头颅
Fanatical legions worshiping at the shine of my father's skull.
以我的名义发动一场战争!每个人都在喊我的名字!
A war in my name! Everyone shouting my name!
保罗
Paul.
保罗·厄崔迪……
Paul Atreides…
你真是你父亲的儿子 你是我的孩子
You are your father's son. You are my son.
你是保罗·厄崔迪公爵
You are Duke Paul Atreides.
你知道你是谁
You know who you are.
放开我!
Get off me!
是你害我这样的!你的边·积利利让我变成了一个怪物!
You did this to me! Your Bene Gesserit made me a freak!
我爸爸死了
My dad is dead.
有人在附近
Someone is near.
你需要喝水
You need to drink.
这是从帐篷里回收的水
It's recycled water from the tent.
汗水和泪水
Sweat and tears.
好吧 我们走吧
All right. Let's get out of here.
是邓肯
It's Duncan.
夫人 保罗……
My Lady. Paul…
-我很抱歉…你父亲…-我们知道
-I'm so sorry… Your father… -We know.
公爵大人
My Lord Duke.
给
Here.
喝这个
Drink this.
哈科宁人同时袭击了星球上所有的人口中心
The Harkonnens hit every population center on the planet at once.
肯定有十个军团 几百艘船
It must've been ten legions, hundreds of ships.
萨道卡尔和他们在一起
There were Sardaukar with them.
-至少两个营  -你确定吗?
-At least two battalions. -Are you sure?
你和萨道卡人交锋 你知道的
You cross swords with the Sardaukar, you know it.
所以 皇帝站在了一边
So, the Emperor's taken a side.
法官怎么说?
What says the Judge of the Change?
皇帝禁止我说任何话
The Emperor forbids me from saying anything at all.
但你冒着生命危险来帮助我们
Yet you risk your life to help us.
暴风雨就要来了
The storm is coming.
几小时后暴风雨就要来了 我们在这里很安全
The storm will be here in a few hours. We'll be safe here.
你知道这是什么地方吗?这是一个古老的生态试验站
Do you know what this place is? It's an old ecological testing station.
他们本来是要驯服这个星球
The were meant to tame the planet
释放沙子下面的水
and free the water locked beneath the sands.
阿拉基斯本可以是一个天堂
Arrakis could have been a paradise.
工作已经开始了 但是香料被发现了
The work had begun but then the spice was discovered.
突然间 没人希望沙漠消失
and suddenly no one wanted the desert to go away.
塔娜特 你能给我们的客人找件合身的衣服吗
Tanat, will you find stillsuits to fit our visitors.
是 列特
Yes, Liet.
-沙米尔 请给我咖啡 -当然 列特
-Shamir, coffee service, please. -Of course, Liet.
你是弗里曼的什么人?
Who are you to the Fremen?
你知道大家族最害怕什么吗 凯恩斯博士?
Do you know what the great houses fear most, Dr. Kynes?
我们这里发生的一切
Exactly what has happened to us here.
萨道卡尔人来了 一个接一个地干掉他们
The Sardaukar coming and picking them off one by one.
只有联合起来 他们才有机会对抗帝国
Only together can they stand a chance against the Imperium.
你能作证吗?
Would you bare witness?
证明皇帝对我们采取了行动
Testify that the Emperor has moved against us here.
如果他们相信我……
If they believe me…
大家族和皇帝之间将会有一场全面战争
There would be general warfare between the great houses and the Emperor.
整个帝国一片混乱
Chaos across the Imperium.
假设我给皇帝提供了一种替代混乱的方法
Let's suppose I present to the Emperor with an alternative to chaos.
皇帝没有儿子 他的女儿也还没有出嫁
And the Emperor has no sons, and his daughters are yet to marry.
你想篡夺王位?
You'd make a play for the throne?
皇帝害怕阿特里德家族 他带你来是要杀你
The Emperor feared the Atreides. He brought you here to kill you.
你有什么不明白的?
What don't you understand?
你是一个躲在地洞里的迷失男孩
You're a lost boy hiding in a hole in the ground.
弗雷曼家族提到了利桑·盖布
The Fremen speak of the Lisan al-Gaib.
小心点
Careful.
来自外部世界的声音 将带领他们进入天堂
The Voice from the Outer World who will lead them to paradise.
迷信
Superstition.
我知道你爱一个弗里曼战士 在战斗中失去了他
I know you loved a Fremen warrior and lost him in battle.
我知道你生活在两个世界 有很多名字
I know you walk in two worlds and are known by many names.
我看到了你的梦
I've seen your dream.
作为皇帝 凯恩斯博士
As Emperor, Dr. Kynes,
我只要挥挥手就能把阿拉基斯变成天堂
I could make a paradise for Arrakis with the wave of my hand.
你真觉得他会是救世主吗?
Do you really think he could be the Mahdi?
他看起来很年轻
He looks very young.
萨尔多卡！
Sardaukar!
-不!邓肯! -保罗,不!
-No! Duncan! -Paul, no!
-邓肯 不！ -他锁门了
-Duncan, no! -He's locked the door.
他走了
He's gone.
邓肯!
Duncan!
我们得走了 我们别无选择
We have to go. We have no choice.
保罗,快跑!
Paul, run!
快点 快点!
Come on, come on!
跟着光线走 你会发现一架扑翼机准备起飞
Follow the light. You'll find a thopter ready to fly.
外面的风暴是你最好的机会
That storm out there is your best shot.
在5000米以上 大部分都是灰尘 爬进去 留在上面
Above 5000 meters, it's mostly dust. Climb into it. Stay on top.
-往南走 找到弗里曼 -你不跟我们一起去?
-Head south. Find the Fremen. -You're not coming with us?
只有两个座位
It only sits two.
我去下一站把这次袭击报告给兰德斯拉德
I'll go to the next station and report this attack to the Landsraad.
如何?
How?
我是弗里曼人 沙漠是我的家
I'm Fremen. The desert is my home.
好运 -好运
-Good luck. -Good luck.
凯恩斯 你背叛了皇帝
Kynes, you have betrayed the emperor.
我只侍奉一个主人
I serve only one master.
他叫沙胡鲁德
His name is Shai-Hulud.
我们后面有喷气式飞机
There are jet flyers behind us.
保罗 我们还不够高!
Paul, we are not high enough!
我不能害怕 恐惧是心灵杀手
I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer.
恐惧是小死亡带来的完全毁灭
Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration.
看见朋友
See the friend.
生命的奥秘不是一个需要解决的问题
The mystery of life isn't a problem to solve.
而是要经历的现实
But a reality to experience.
一个无法通过停止它来理解的进程
A process that cannot be understand by stopping it.
我们必须随着进程的进展而前进
We must move with the flow of the process.
我们必须加入它 我们必须随波逐流
We must join it. We must float with it.
让它去吧 让它去吧
Let it go. Let it go.
他还没有完全痊愈
He hasn't fully healed yet.
我们把他们追进了科里奥利风暴
We chased them into a Coriolis storm.
风速为每小时800公里
Wind's at 800 kilometers an hour.
没有东西能在这样的风暴中幸存
Nothing survives such a storm.
他们死了 这是一个必然
They're dead. It's a certainty.
终于完成了
So it's done finally.
传话给吉迪擎天王让他开始出售我们的香料储备
Send word to Giedi Prime to begin selling our spice reserves.
但进展缓慢 我们不希望价格下降
But slowly. We don't want the price to fall.
你不知道我花了多少钱才把这么强大的力量带到屏障上
You have no idea how much it cost me to bring such a force to barrier.
现在我只有一个要求 收入
Now I only have one requirement. Income.
所以 挤压 拉班 用力挤压
So, squeeze, Rabban. Squeeze hard.
是 叔叔
Yes, uncle.
弗里曼人呢?
And the Fremen?
杀光他们
Kill them all.
我们在5000米以上
We're above 5000 meters.
我们一着陆 就跑向岩石
As soon as we land, run for the rocks.
你用这个呼吸
You breathe with this.
现在我们得找到弗里曼人
Now we have to find the Fremen.
你还好吗? -是的
-Are you good? -Yeah.
保罗……
Paul…
别害怕
Don't be frightened.
即使是一只小沙漠鼠也能存活
Even a little desert mouse can survive.
你需要面对你的恐惧
You'll need to face your fears.
朋友会帮助你
A friend will help you.
跟随朋友
Follow the friend.
你还有很多要学
You have much to learn.
我也必指示你旷野的路
And I will show you the ways of the desert.
跟我来
Come with me.
西斯 邓肯住的地方
The sietch, where Duncan lived.
那边的某个地方
Somewhere off that way.
我能看见那边的绿色
I can see the green over there.
那儿
There.
这意味着弗里曼人住在那里
That means Fremen live there.
我们天黑后过河 弗里曼人就是这么做的
We'll cross after dark. That's how the Fremen do it.
我们就要进入蠕虫的领地了
We're about to enter worm territory.
我们不能像普通人一样走路 如果那样……我们就死定了
We can't walk like regular humans, if we do - we're dead.
我们得像弗莱曼人一样走路 这叫沙漠漫步
We'll have to walk like the Fremen do. It's called the sand walk.
至少根据国内的电影书籍
At least according to the film books back home.
是的 是的 我知道了
Yeah. Yeah, I've got it.
好吧 跟着我 做同样的动作
Okay, follow me. Do the same moves.
我认为这是正确的方向
I think this is the right direction.
就在附近 我们从这里出去吧
It's close by. Let's get out of here.
等等
Wait.
是鼓沙
It's drum sand.
快跑!
Run!
走!走!
Go! Go!
是一个巨人
It's a thumper.
有人引爆了炸弹
Someone set off a thumper.
保罗,快跑!
Paul, run!
它们有多大？这太疯狂了
How big are they? That was insane.
有人召唤他
Someone called him.
我们并不孤单
We are not alone.
别跑
Do not run.
你只会浪费身体的水分
You will only waste your bodies water.
拿着
Hold.
斯蒂尔加
Stilgar.
嘿 你了解我的 你去我父亲的御前会议时我也在场
Hey, you know me. I was there when you came to my father's council.
这是公爵的儿子
This is the Duke's son.
还等什么？我们需要他们的水
Why are you waiting? We need their water.
这就是我跟你说过的那个男孩 我们不能碰他
This is the boy I told you about. We can't touch him.
-他是利桑·盖布？-他还没有证明自己
-Is he Lisan al-Gaib? -He hasn't proved himself.
他们是弱者 -杰米斯……
-They're weaklings. -Jamis…
他们在沙胡鲁德的路上勇敢地穿越了一次
There was a brave crossing they made in the path of Shai-Hulud.
他说话和行动都不像个懦夫
He does not speak or act like a weakling.
他的父亲也不像
Nor did his father.
我的重击器救了他的命
My thumper saved his life.
冷静点 斯蒂加 他不是命中注定的那个人
Go back to reason, Stilgar. He's not The One.
我们有强大的朋友
We have powerful friends.
你帮我们离开这个世界 去卡拉丹 你会得到丰厚的回报
You help us off world, to Caladan, you will be well rewarded.
在你肉体之外 你能提供什么财富呢?
What wealth can you offer beyond the water in your flesh.
这个男孩很年轻 他可以学习我们的方法
The boy is young. He can learn our ways.
他可能有避难所
He may have sanctuary.
但是这个女人没有受过训练
But the woman isn't trained
也太老了 学不了
and too old to learn.
回来 你们这些狗！
Back, you dogs!
她会割断我的喉咙
She'll cut my throat.
你为什么不说你是个古怪的女人 还是个斗士?
Why didn't you say you were a weirding woman and a fighter?
谈话很简短
The conversation ran short.
和平 女人 和平
Peace, woman, peace.
我判断错了
I misjudged.
太阳升起来了 我们必须到达塔布西斯
The sun is rising. We must reach Sietch Tabr.
陌生人的命运将在那里决定
The fate of the strangers will be decided there.
在那之前 他们由我保护
Until then, they are under my protection.
我向你保证
I give you my word.
我不会让你伤害我的朋友
I would not have let you hurt my friends.
他们说你是救世主
They say you are the Mahdi.
但你看起来像个小男孩
But you look like a little boy.
你选了一条最艰难的路 跟我来
You chose the hardest way up. Follow me.
起飞!起飞!
Take off! Take off!
把它给我
Give it to me.
你应该有自己的毛拉手枪 当你赢得它的时候
You would have your own maula pistol when you've earned it.
把它给我
Give it to me.
查妮 负责新来的人 确保他们在旅途中安全
Chani, take charge of the newcomers. See that they are safe in the journey.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我不要他们
I will not have them.
杰米斯 我说过了 安静些
Jamis, I have spoken. Be still.
你说话像个领袖 而且是最强的领袖
You talk like a leader, but the strongest leads.
她打败了你
She bested you.
我祈求阿姆塔尔
I invoke the Amtal.
-你不能挑战萨亚迪娜 -那谁会以她的名义战斗?
-You may not challenge a sayyadina. -Then who will fight in her name?
杰米斯 别这样 别 夜色渐深
Jamis, don't do this. Don't. The night is fading.
太阳将见证这死亡
Then the sun will witness this death.
她的冠军在哪里?
Where is her champion?
我接受她的冠军
I accept her champion.
保罗·厄崔迪必须为……
Paul Atreides must die…
奎萨兹·哈德拉赫的崛起而死
for Kwisatz Haderach to rise.
别害怕 别抗拒
Don't be frightened. Don't resist.
当你夺走别人的生命时 你也夺走了自己的生命
When you take a life, you take your own.
我不相信你是利桑·盖布
I don't believe you are the Lisan al-Gaib.
但我希望你死得光荣
But I want you to die with honor.
这把水晶刀是我姑婆送给我的
This crysknife was given to me by my great-aunt.
它是由一种巨大的沙虫沙胡鲁德的牙齿制成的
It's made from a tooth of Shai-Hulud, the great sand worm.
如果你拿着它死去 那将是莫大的荣耀
This would be a great honor if you to die holding it.
外部世界在哪里?
Where is the outworlder?
杰米斯是个好战士 他不会让你受苦的
Jamis is a good fighter. He won't let you suffer.
查尼……
Chani…
不要紧
Never mind.
愿你的刀碎成碎片
May your knife chip and shatter.
你应该欢迎我的刀锋
You should welcome my blade.
这个世界会杀了你
This world will kill you.
这样更快
Quicker this way.
你屈服吗?
Do you yield?
这孩子不知道我们的规则
The boy does not know our rule.
在阿姆塔尔规则下没有屈服 只有死亡是对此的考验
There is no yielding under the Amtal rule, only death is the test of that.
他在戏弄他吗? -不
-Is he toying with him? -No.
保罗从未杀过人
Paul has never killed a man.
克维萨茨·哈德拉赫
Kwisatz Haderach.
爬上 上升
Climb up. Rise.
你现在是我们的一员了 一命换一命
You're one of us now. A life for a life.
-跟我们去塔布西斯吧 -不
-Come with us to Sietch Tabr. -No.
保罗需要离开这个世界
Paul needs to get off world.
你一定有办法 你有走私者 你有船只
You must have ways. You have smugglers, you have ships.
-不 -你有……
-No. -You have--
是皇帝派我们来的
The Emperor sent us to this place.
我父亲来……
And my father came…
不是为了香料 不是为了财富
Not for spice, not for the riches,
而是因为你的人民的力量
but for the strength of your people.
我的路通向沙漠
My road leads into the desert.
我能看到
I could see it.
如果你愿意 我们会来的
If you'll have us, we will come.
沙漠力量
Desert power.
这仅仅是个开始
This is only the beginning.
汉化：@大月半子（PPm）
https://weibo.com/baba